Daeho once suffered
from a long and unusual drought.
It was so bad that it even caused
Lake Gyeongcheondaeho
to completely dry up.
The mages of Daeho performed a grand rite
to fill the lake back up with energy.
Then enormous hailstones
started falling from the sky.
But among the many hailstones,
there was one that did not melt.
This unmelting hailstone
first turned into fire,
then stone,
and then water.
Then it turned back
into its original form, ice.
In that process, it produced black powder.
This powder was called the Soul Ejector,
which was used in the alchemy of souls.
The power of the Soul Ejector
was truly astonishing.
One could bring the dead back to life
by summoning back their souls.
One could shift souls
from one body to another.
One could even expel
the soul of the living
and steal their energy.
Eventually, that boundless power
ended up causing chaos.
In order to possess the unmelting ice
that produced the Soul Ejector,
the battle of mages turned into bloodshed,
and Daeho became a living hell.
The man who ended the long-lasting battle
was Master Seo Gyeong,
the founder of Songrim.
I was his pupil.
That ice stone sounds amazing.
Where is it? I would like to see it.
It is an extremely frightening stone.
Sorcery using the stone's power
created wicked things
that could hurt people.
Boy, where did you get that wooden doll?
I found it up in the mountain.
Would you like to trade it for this?
Yes.
This is a relic cursed with sorcery.
-What was that?
That was a dangerous item
created with sorcery.
I know what they are.
They are called relics.
Jinyowon has lots of them.
That is right.
Inside Jinyowon, there are relics
that are much more dangerous.
There, you will find many peculiar items
that were made
with the power of the ice stone.
They sit there waiting for an opportunity
to come out into the world again.
Should I take you in?
No, thank you.
I may be a filthy girl
whom everyone avoids,
but I refuse to serve just anyone.
Damn it. How dare she.
She should have been grateful.
This batch of cinnamon and ginger wine
has quite a strong scent of cinnamon.
Thank you, Your Royal Highness.
It smells of cinnamon.
That impudent girl.
Is there something bothering you?
The filth from Filthy Mu-deok
must have gotten on me.
The stench will not go away.
It smells wonderful.
Forget it. Get out.
Leave already.
Yes, Your Royal Highness.
I showed her mercy
and saved her from trouble.
I even gave her my sachet
and a silk dress.
How ungrateful of her.
-I am grateful.
-I told you to leave…
Filthy Mu-deok?
How did you get in here?
I have that sachet you gave me.
You must be here
because you need something from me again.
You have been thinking about me,
Your Royal Highness,
so I came to see you.
Are you saying you can read my mind?
Good.
Have a glass of cinnamon and ginger wine
that is a lot stronger than the last one.
It smells wonderful.
It does?
I must say, I really like this place.
I hope you continue to think of me
just like you did today.
I will come to visit whenever you do.
The palace is a great place.
You get to dress in silk,
and it is filled with different kinds
of aromatic wine.
But do you know
why I keep thinking of you?
Because you are Filthy Mu-deok.
But right now, you do not reek of filth.
Your Royal Highness.
Who are you?
You caught me.
Something wicked just came in here.
-Search around.
-Yes, Your Royal Highness.
Why did it show up looking like Mu-deok?
Search every corner again.
-Yes, my lady.
The Crown Prince is here.
The Crown Prince?
I am in search of someone.
I was told that she would be here.
Is there something going on?
There seems to be a disturbance.
A maid caused trouble and disappeared,
so we were looking for her.
A maid?
She does not work for us.
Her name is Mu-deok.
She serves the Jang family.
She is whom I am looking for.
Did something happen?
That maid…
accidentally broke the yin-and-yang jade
that was going to be used
to make my wedding rings.
I told you to be careful.
What will you do now?
I apologize, my lady.
Please forgive me.
I will ask her owner to come here.
Take her away
and lock her up in the annex.
I am sorry!
Forgive me, my lady!
She must have been scared
about getting punished.
While she was locked up,
she stole the jade and ran away.
Seeing as we still have not found her,
it looks as if she has
already fled this place.
She got scared and ran away?
A bold girl like her?
Mages from Jeongjingak are here to visit.
Your Royal Highness, what brings you here?
What about you, Yul?
To look for someone.
Did you also come here
looking for Mu-deok?
Yes.
I am here for Mu-deok.
She broke the yin-and-yang jade,
then ran away with it
to avoid getting punished.
But why did you not
get the wedding rings made?
I went to Chwiseonru to lend you my hand,
but I heard you already had left.
I just decided to postpone it.
Yul, why are you looking for Mu-deok?
I also saw the exact same illusion as you,
Your Royal Highness.
How did you enter Songrim?
I came because you kept longing for me.
What do you mean?
You were longing for
the one you met at Danhyanggok.
Stop fooling around.
I was longing for you?
-I have never done that.
-You are lying.
You kept the whistle.
The broken leg did not bother you.
And you were not scared to get scolded.
Because you liked her a lot.
Continue to think about her like that.
Then I will come to see you.
You…
are not human.
Are you going to get rid of me?
Then you will never get to see me again.
It was not her. It was an illusion.
Does that mean
what I saw was also an illusion?
It was odd, so I went to Chwiseonru
looking for Mu-deok.
They told me she was dragged here.
She was not dragged here.
She was here to run an errand.
And she disappeared
with something precious.
We are in search of a thief,
not an illusion.
There is her owner.
Is Master Lee not here today again?
He is a man who wanders like the wind.
He left me the dog and left.
Was Gwigu also made from the ice stone?
Master Seo Gyeong made this
with the energy from the ice stone
in hopes of finding traces of sorcery.
Uk broke Gwigu's pottery,
so Master Lee
summoned the spirit from Jinyowon
and put it inside this dog.
Do you really not know
where Master Seo Gyeong
sealed the ice stone?
I do not know.
Do you think the alchemy of souls
started to occur again
because someone managed
to unseal the ice stone?
The only way for someone to shift souls
without mastering Hwansu
is by using the ice stone.
I am certain that someone
unsealed the ice stone
and brought it out into the world again.
Well, that is not good.
We cannot let the disaster
from 200 years ago repeat itself.
We must find the ice stone.
I was given orders to give this to you.
I thought you were
going to lie low for a while.
Are you planning on
shifting another person's soul?
Tell them that I safely received this.
I will.
Hurry up and find a eunuch
who can replace him.
Your soul will be shifted into that body,
so choose wisely.
Yes, sir.
I did not serve the Danju
just to shift my soul
into a eunuch's body.
I will use Naksu
to get the body I want.
My maid has committed a disgraceful act.
I am fully responsible as her master.
I apologize.
You must be upset about having lost
the jade to be used for the wedding rings.
I pleaded to my mother
for that yin-and-yang jade.
Yin-and-yang jade wedding rings
allow couples to have
a long and happy marriage.
But it is broken now.
I did not know that
it held such a deep meaning.
I must say, I am upset too.
We will find you a more valuable jade
for the wedding rings.
I appreciate your sincere apology.
-You may all leave now.
-Thank you.
I cannot do that.
I need to find Mu-deok.
I want to find that wicked maid
and have her return the yin-and-yang jade.
She is weak and she has short legs,
so she will not have traveled far.
I would like your permission to stay
and look for her myself.
You have my permission.
Thank you.
Now that I have your permission,
I would like you to open the door.
Open the door to Jinyowon,
where relics and artifacts reside.
Jinyowon's entrance can only be opened
by a member of the Jin family.
Right now, Cho-yeon and I are
the only ones who can open this door.
There is no way she is in there.
I saw Mu-deok's illusion.
Maybe you were dreaming.
How can you be sure that
it was an illusion created by a relic?
I saw it too.
It was an illusion disguised as Mu-deok.
All the relics that have the power
to create illusions are inside Jinyowon.
Let us go inside and check.
All right. I will open the door.
However, this place is filled
with dangerous relics and artifacts.
You could be possessed by sorcery
and be unable to return.
Young Master, it is too dangerous.
I will go with him.
As will I.
It sounds fun.
When will I get a chance
to enter Jinyowon again?
Go on inside.
I will give you an hour.
We should tell the leader.
Mu-deok.
Mu-deok!
So this is Jinyowon.
They say everything here is so precious.
Not a single one can be bought with money.
Will you please be quiet?
We are not here on a tour.
You are not the owner.
But I guess that could change
if you marry into the Jin family.
Lucky you.
All these precious treasures
will become yours, Jin Uk.
If you envy me so much,
you can marry into this family instead.
But even if you do become the owner,
how will you control anything?
You are a low-level mage.
If you are so great,
can you touch anything here?
The leader of Jinyowon told us
not to touch anything.
What an excuse.
You are just too scared to touch them.
-Damn it.
-What was that?
I do not know. What was that?
Are you all right?
Something odd must be in there.
Were you not startled?
I was startled.
It is dark in here, so be careful.
Was he really startled?
Yes. When Yul gets startled,
he loses his sense of direction.
Yul, do not go that way!
It is the other way.
We must go that way.
Let us all be careful.
Yul is always so calm,
but he can be a scatterbrain
when he is startled too.
I guess so.
Just make sure to be careful.
Be careful yourself.
Wait for me.
How did I get stuck in here?
I should have held it in.
I should not have provoked her.
I told you to be careful.
You wait here.
Young Master Jang will be here soon.
Young Lady Jin,
what is going to happen to me now?
What do you think?
You will be severely punished.
No, that is not what I am worried about.
They say whoever breaks
the yin-and-yang jade
will never have
a long-lasting relationship.
What am I going to do now?
What do you mean?
Stop talking nonsense.
If you break the yin-and-yang jade,
they say the person you love
will never love you back.
I heard all the gisaengs
at Chwiseonru saying that.
Is that true?
Yes.
Did you not know that, Young Lady Jin?
That cannot be.
Then what is going to happen to me?
Why are you worried
when I was the one who broke it?
You broke the jade, did you not?
You made me carry it
so you could blame it on me.
Am I right?
If you felt so wronged, you should have
said something to my mother.
Had I humiliated her daughter
in front of everyone,
she would not have forgiven me.
I am not scared of you,
but I am scared of your mother,
the leader of Jinyowon.
Are you that afraid of your mother?
It is true that I fear my mother,
but I hate you just as much.
I will sell you.
Like you said, my mother is a scary woman.
You will get sold
as punishment for having broken the jade.
To place far away!
Did she run away?
Should I try climbing over this wall?
How did she open the door to Jinyowon?
So this is Jinyowon.
If she gets locked inside, she might die.
Hey.
So it is you.
It has been a long time.
You cannot leave.
It will not break.
Nothing will work!
Be quiet.
Could she have died since she is
incapable of practicing spells?
If they saw her as an illusion…
Young Lady Jin.
Every time you move, I hear a sound.
It sounds…
like jade clinking against each other.
Mu-deok!
The hour is up. We must leave.
I am not going. I must find her.
This place is too big and deep.
The three of us cannot find her here.
You only came in here for a tour,
so you may go ahead and leave.
How did you see an illusion of Mu-deok?
I do not know where it came from.
But…
I came because you kept longing for me.
That is right.
She said that to me too.
That she came because I thought of her.
So her illusion comes to see you
if you think about her?
I guess you did not see it.
She visited me and Yul,
but she did not visit you
even though you are her owner.
Why in the world
were you thinking about Mu-deok?
I was drinking cinnamon and ginger wine.
Were you the one who got her drunk
and made her reek of cinnamon?
That is correct.
I also gave her a sachet that day.
The smell of cinnamon
probably came from the sachet.
Oh, you mean the sachet
that she hung by the outhouse
to get rid of flies?
"By the outhouse"?
Thank you, Your Royal Highness.
It really helped shoo away the flies.
Yul, what were you doing
when you saw her illusion?
The mirror.
-My mirror broke.
-So did the one in my room.
Did it come from the mirror?
A mirror?
Could this be it?
That is not you. It is fake.
It is an illusion.
So it was you.
She is trapped inside the mirror?
Yes.
We cannot see what is inside,
but we are sure she is in there.
She was sucked into the Mirror of Longing.
"The Mirror of Longing"?
It is a relic that creates illusions.
It uses other mirrors
to show illusions of things
that people long for.
She knows no spells,
so she probably got sucked inside
while she was in front of it.
We need to get Mu-deok out of the mirror.
Our spells will not work
because the energy in there is too strong.
Please take the Mirror of Longing
out of Jinyowon.
That cannot be done.
That relic swallowed a human.
It is too dangerous to take it outside.
I order you as the Crown Prince.
Take out the Mirror of Longing.
The Unanimous Assembly has granted us
a plaque to protect Jinyowon
from a situation like this.
I cannot take it out
even if it is the King's orders.
Uk will not leave…
without Mu-deok.
Then he will have to stay inside.
Once the hour is over,
I am going to seal this door.
Mother.
I found the yin-and-yang jade.
Mu-deok must not have stolen it.
Now that I found the jade,
please take out the Mirror of Longing
and get Mu-deok out of there.
Young Master Jang will die
if he gets locked inside.
Stay out of this.
Once the agreed time is over,
I shall seal the door.
Do not waste your energy.
You know you do not have
the power to break it.
Shut it! You are nothing but an illusion.
That is right. I am an illusion.
An illusion that reflects who you are.
Humans are incapable
of seeing themselves with their own eyes.
The only way is
to see themselves through a mirror.
So the perception you have about yourself
is nothing but an illusion.
The same goes for how others perceive you.
They only see what they want to see
and create an illusion that suits them.
It is all just an illusion.
If what you say is true,
that means people
only see illusions and nothing else.
That is right.
I turn into what they want to see the most
and show it to them.
I shall do the same for you.
Give me your energy.
Then I will…
turn you into
the most perfect version of yourself.
But…
you need my reflection
to create that so-called illusion.
What?
If there is nothing to reflect,
a mirror becomes useless.
You are nothing but a piece of glass.
That is enough babbling from you.
Mu-deok!
Are you in there?
Uk.
Uk!
Uk, I am in here!
I found you.
The time is up.
Cho-yeon, seal that door.
Mother.
-Do it now.
-Please wait.
I would like to go inside.
If the relic cannot be brought outside,
I will go in there myself
and get her out of the Mirror of Longing.
How can I trust a high-level mage
to set foot in there?
Trust me.
I will not touch any other artifacts.
I am not sure if I can.
My trust was once broken
by a Songrim mage.
Have you ever allowed
a Songrim mage to enter Jinyowon?
If you want to save Jang Uk,
you will have to ask mages
from Jeongjingak to drag him out of there.
My lord.
We are running out of time.
Yul, I want you to go in there
and bring Uk out.
Mu-deok.
While you were gone,
I thought about…
what I could do
to keep you by my side.
If I become Cheonbugwan's Gwanju,
you can be the Assistant Gwanju.
Why would I want that?
You said you did not want
to stay by my side as just a maid.
We cannot tell anyone
that you are my master.
But you can stay
if you become the Assistant Gwanju.
Cheonbugwan's Gwanju
keeping a soul shifter by his side?
You must be mad.
I thought about it
after I heard about my marriage.
"He finally has a way out."
"But how will I manage without him?"
I bet you thought that and felt lost.
But now that you are not here,
I feel just as lost.
Mu-deok.
I miss you.
Feign ignorance even if I get caught.
No one here will let that thing attack me.
Then do me a favor, Uk.
Take me up there.
Fine.
I will take you to the top of that tree.
Mu-deok.
What is happening?
She is here!
Who?
It is her, the blind girl!
It is the ice stone!
The mirror is going to shatter.
Step away.
Young Master.
Mu-deok.
-Are you all right?
-Yes, I am fine.
-Is Mu-deok all right as well?
-Of course.
I fell while bringing out
the yin-and-yang jade.
I think that was when the jade broke.
So you tried to blame a maid
for the already-broken jade.
And the Mirror of Longing?
It was next to me when I fell,
but I did not even touch it.
Uk is not strong enough
to break the Mirror of Longing.
Then I must have
harmed the mirror as I fell.
Did you also
lock Mu-deok inside Jinyowon?
I did seal the door,
but she walked inside herself.
Those who are not members
of the Jin family cannot open that door.
Are you saying Mu-deok opened it?
Then I must have
opened the door.
I just saw her go inside
and locked her in there out of anger.
I apologize.
I will tell everyone
to keep things quiet.
I shall also stay silent about this
to help you save face.
I am truly sorry.
Are you all right?
Can you still not see?
No.
I saw a really bright light
when the mirror broke.
I cannot seem to open my eyes.
We should cover your eyes then.
Here.
If you stare at the sun for too long,
you are not able to see for a while.
You will recover soon.
I am sorry for this.
You did nothing wrong.
Young Lady Jin is at fault.
Mu-deok, are you all right?
What are you doing here,
Young Master Park?
I came because I was worried.
I see you have hurt your eyes.
Young Master Seo, you came as well?
You should get treated at Sejukwon.
I will take you there right now.
The palace is near, so she can go there.
Your Royal Highness? You are here too?
I will take you to the royal clinic.
That is not necessary.
She was just blinded by the light.
She did not get hurt.
I know you did not plan any of this,
but they came here for you.
So you should apologize and thank them.
I apologize for troubling you.
Thank you all.
Young Master.
Let us go home.
After what happened today,
I do not know
if their marriage will proceed.
Did you hear what she said?
She was ready to seal the door
even though Young Master was inside.
How terrifying.
It makes me uneasy that he will live
with a mother-in-law like her.
She made that choice to protect Jinyowon.
When you have a lot to protect,
you sometimes have no choice
but to be heartless.
Then…
would you have done the same?
I would say you and I are pretty close.
What if I got locked inside?
Would you seal the door?
So heartlessly?
My goodness.
It seems like you would.
Even if it means I might die in there?
Do not put me in a difficult spot
over something
that has not even happened.
I am not even actually locked inside.
Does it hurt for you to lie and tell me
-that you will never seal the door?
-I cannot
lie to you.
Right.
That is what someone like you must do.
You should say hello to Young Master Jang.
No. I have nothing to say to him.
I cannot lie
and act like everything is fine.
Of course. Thank you for today.
Goodbye.
Maidservant Kim…
If I ever have to seal the door,
it would shatter my heart…
to pieces.
He is inflexible and slow-witted.
"How could I seal the door
if you are inside?"
Could you not have said that?
What you did was dangerous.
Entering Jinyowon
was recklessly childish
and stubborn of you.
Do not be so angry.
You may think I am pathetic,
but that is an illusion.
What?
The mirror I saw inside Jinyowon told me
that people only see
what they wish to see.
That it is an illusion.
Are you saying I see you as an illusion?
If not,
why do you not want me to do anything?
All my life, I tried so hard
to prove to everyone
that I was my father's son.
But…
you told me I was not.
Though it hurt, it got rid of my illusion.
But even after that,
why do you want me to stay as an illusion?
I do not care what you stay as.
I only wish for one thing.
And that is for you…
to be safe.
The illusion I tried so hard to prove
no longer exists.
So from now on,
I am going to try even harder
to find out who I really am
and what I must do from now on.
Can you see now?
Yes, I can see.
What?
I was told the mirror made illusions.
I am checking
if it is really you that I saved.
You did not save me.
I broke it and got out myself.
What?
When I was trapped inside the mirror,
I regained my power for a bit
just like how I did
in Lake Gyeongcheondaeho.
I am sure I broke the mirror
with my own power.
So that was how you got out?
I was excited thinking it was me.
Not even close.
You should be grateful
that the mirror did not suck you in.
I even thought about that
because you were still inside.
What a futile idea.
It would not have traded you for me.
What if it did?
Then would it not have been futile?
Well, I would have survived.
And I would have died.
Listen to me, my pupil.
When there is no other way,
the best deal is
to sacrifice yourself and save me.
No way.
If I die, you should die too.
You cannot live on your own.
You have no other choice.
When you put your pupil in danger,
your life should be at risk too.
Fine. I will keep that in mind.
Then what will happen
to marrying the woman
who almost had your master killed?
Marrying her will
surely guarantee my safety.
But you almost lost your life,
so I should risk my life too.
This is a marriage of convenience.
So let us resolve our issues
after the wedding.
The reason you need
a son-in-law like me is that
I am the eldest of the Jang family
and the next potential Gwanju
of Cheonbugwan.
Our families will come together
and become stronger.
Yes. Because this is
a marriage of convenience,
we should be open
about our strengths and weaknesses.
Apparently, I am not the son
of Cheonbugwan's Gwanju, Jang Gang.
I do not care about such rumors.
But what if that rumor
turns out to be true?
Think about whether or not you are willing
to take that risk
and take me in as your son-in-law.
I see you still have
the binding bracelet on you.
Yes.
He is still impudent as ever.
Why did you decide to marry Cho-yeon off
without even discussing it with me?
Who are you to meddle
in our family matters?
Ho-gyeong.
I am also a member of the Jin family.
The surname "Jin" is only given to those
with mothers from the Jin family.
My mother was a fool to have given
our family surname to someone
who my father begot out of wedlock.
You kicked me out as soon as you became
the leader of Jinyowon.
Do you still resent me that much?
I do not resent you.
I detest you.
I detest how treacherous you are.
The leader of Jinyowon should not
make decisions based on preference.
Choosing Jang Uk was the wrong decision.
Cancel the marriage.
What?
I will give you
a better card than Jang Uk.
How about the Crown Prince
as your son-in-law?
You want the Crown Prince
to marry into our family and live with us?
Cho-yeon is the second daughter.
Bu-yeon is the eldest
and will lead the family.
Her future husband will
move in with the family,
so it is unnecessary for Cho-yeon.
What are you scheming?
How dare you talk about Bu-yeon.
I know that your husband is
still looking for Bu-yeon.
As the Assistant Gwanju of Cheonbugwan,
I will do everything in my power
to help you find the daughter
you hopelessly long for.
I will make Bu-yeon the leader of Jinyowon
and make Cho-yeon become the queen.
So please
do not have her marry Uk.
I, your brother,
will become Cheonbugwan's Gwanju
and give great support to Jinyowon.
After all, I am a member
of the Jin family.
Yul, there is something I find quite odd.
Why were you thinking about Mu-deok?
I was not thinking about Mu-deok.
I also do not understand
why that illusion showed up as Mu-deok
-and said those things.
-What did it say?
Hey, Yul.
We have to go this way.
Why do you keep wandering?
What startled you?
I will be all right.
Oh, dear.
Delivery packages.
Young Lady Jin's marriage gifts will
probably get delivered to Songrim today.
It is best that no one sees them.
I should keep them safe.
The bird! Catch the bird!
-Oh, gosh!
-Run!
-Darn it.
-Where did it fly to?
-Come on.
-It is over there!
-Gosh.
-Darn it.
-Hey.
-Over there!
Naksu has the ability to shift souls.
If Naksu shifted souls,
she is probably still alive somewhere.
You were longing for
the one you met at Danhyanggok.
Continue to think about her like that.
Then I will come to see you.
It is actually warmer than you think.
The snow quickly melts in the sunny spots.
So Mu-deok…
was Naksu.
You were the one
who left this at Danhyanggok.
So you are alive, Naksu.
Mu-deok.
I waited ages for you.
Did Maidservant Kim not tell you?
You should have come by noon.
Let us hurry. We must get
to Danhyanggok before the sun sets.
Instead of Danhyanggok,
let us go somewhere else.
Where?
There is an empty temple
by the bamboo forest in the east.
We can go there.
Bring Jang Uk here tonight.
Then I shall spare your life.
I must hand you over so I can live.
It is what must be done.
The marriage will not happen.
I gave them an excuse to discard me.
I see.
But…
Maidservant Kim had already received
the yin-and-yang jade.
So I made something out of it.
-They are bird's eggs.
-Yes.
Pick one. We can have one each.
We have quite a peculiar relationship.
A young master and a maid.
A master and a pupil.
So I figured they could act
as a token to remind us
to stay loyal and dutiful.
I will choose first.
I pick red. You can have the blue one.
Master, let us stay loyal
and dutiful to each other.
-Uk.
-Yes?
This is where we say goodbye.
I will return to where I came from.
-But they abandoned you.
-I met them again today.
They know who I am.
They asked me to come back.
-I thought they were dangerous.
-As you can see, I am alive.
If they wanted to kill me,
they would have already.
If I go back,
I will be able to regain my energy.
I promised to do that for you…
I told you that
I would stand on a cliff and push you.
I admit that I overtrained you every time,
and you did your best.
-We can keep doing that.
-No.
If we stay together, you will die,
and I will get caught.
What brings the leader of Songrim
to secretly come all the way here?
I have something to ask you
about a Cheonbugwan mage
named Cho Chung from 20 years ago.
Naksu's father, Cho Chung,
was a soul shifter.
When we found him,
he had already run wild
and killed everyone in his family.
The four families had to get involved
to stop any further killings.
Naksu's father was also a soul shifter?
In the eyes of a child,
we probably seemed like murderers
for having killed her father.
She must have thought
her father was murdered by us.
That is probably why she came
to Songrim as an assassin.
What is the important matter
that you wanted to talk about?
Do you recall anything about Naksu?
If we meet again, I will kill you.
Are you implying that
I took in Cho Chung's daughter
and trained her to become an assassin?
You burned her body
as soon as it was found.
Was that not because you did not want
her identity to get revealed?
I will tell you what happened 20 years ago
instead of saying what you wish to hear.
Here, at Cheonbugwan, we record stars
from 1 a.m. to 3 a.m.,
when energy is the highest.
The Gwanju checks it at noon,
and the recorded plate gets stored here.
But one day, a constellation plate
recorded that morning disappeared.
Fortunately, we were able
to find it again.
What about that?
It was the day Jang Gang's wife,
Do-hwa, died and Jang Uk was born.
Cho Chung recorded the stars that day,
and I was the one
who found the missing plate.
I have managed to sneak out
the actual plate.
The one in Cheonbugwan is
a fake one without the King's Star.
Are you telling me
that you know what happened
on the day that Jang Gang's son,
Jang Uk, was born?
A star that could change the world
appeared in the sky.
You knew about the King's Star?
Do you think things stayed quiet
thanks to Cho Chung's death?
Who do you think turned him
into a soul shifter in the first place?
Do not ask questions
you do not wish to hear the answers to.
That is the only way
to protect Songrim and its people.
The Danju does not know
that you are still alive, Naksu.
I did not tell him.
Bring Jang Uk.
Then my lips will stay sealed.
I shall shift my soul into his body.
Where is Jang Uk?
He will be here soon.
What brings you here at such a late hour?
Before Uk was born…
About 20 years ago…
Did Jang Gang
master a type of sorcery?
perform the alchemy of souls?
What is taking him so long?
It is finally raining.
He should be here now.
Did you fool me?
Why are you stalling?
Seeing that the Danju
still has not shown up,
you really must be
the only one who knows about me.
You little…
Our journey stops here.
What about the empty temple by the forest?
Why were you going to take me there?
I was going to hand you over
so I could live.
Now you know, so do not follow me.
Then you should not have told me
about the temple.
How could I not follow you
after hearing what you just said?
I am more upset than you are.
I gave up my chance to live
just because of a bird's egg.
I am glad I reminded you
to be loyal and dutiful.
I could have actually died.
Now that I have helped you escape death,
fight like your life depends on it,
my pupil.
You make it sound like you saved my life.
If the cloudy sky blesses us with rain,
then we both might be able to live.
You really are one lucky fellow, Uk.
It is raining cats and dogs.
Do you not think my opponent
is a bit too strong?
He is a Cheonbugwan mage.
Hi. You remember me, right?
It is time. Use Tansu.
Instead of trying to flick the waterdrops
with your uncontrollable sword,
wield the sword
so that waterdrops fall onto it.
No.
What is that?
The alchemy of souls.
Is my soul…
being shifted right now?
Jang Uk!
So you have shifted souls
with my pupil, Gil-ju.
I think Uk fell victim
to the alchemy of souls.
What?
Was the man who shifted my father's soul
Jin Mu of Cheonbugwan?
Why is it you again?
Are you certain that
the ice stone was indeed destroyed?
Order all of our mages to look for Gil-ju.
It must never be revealed
that they are soul shifters.
Subtitle translation by: Ja-won Lee